Welcome to this video about the exercise task
about the vector graphics example. In this
task, first of all, we have a class
diagram, which consists of five classes. And
we shall say which method or which classes
can invoke the methods scale, color, rotate,
move, and extent, which are the methods of
Picture here. So, when we look at this class
diagram, we see those methods only within
the Picture class. So, that is why we could
simply say, of course, all objects of class
Picture could call those methods.
But, as
the Picture class is an abstract class, there
are no such objects. That's why we could consider
the other classes. Circle, Rectangle, and
Path are all also pictures because they inherit
from the Picture class. And that is why they
also inherit the methods. That is why objects
of types circle, rectangle, and Path can also
invoke those methods. And so, circle, rectangle,
and Path can all invoke those mentioned methods.
But for Point, this is not true. So, because
Point is in relation with Path by an aggregation,
Points cannot invoke these methods. For instance,
if you have gotten an object of type Point,
it's not possible to call scale on it. The
second part of this task is about completing
the class diagram, which is mentioned above.
Especially, we've got underscores here within
the Picture class. And therefore, we require
the slides of the lecture, more specifically
the vector graphics example when it was introduced.
Because there we have the operations or the
functions defined which are the basis for
the methods which we've got in this class
here. And this function always takes a Picture
and then more arguments and returns a picture.
In our case, we've got the object-oriented view
of this now. And we've got a Picture
already. On the specific Picture, we call
such methods. So, we will call scale on a
specific picture. And when we do that, we
require further arguments. But we change the
Picture at hand. That is why we do not require
a Picture as an argument. And when we have got
scale, we shall use the UML syntax here. We
also require a name for the arguments. And
for scale, we, of course, would scale within
the x and y direction. So, we require an x
and a y value. This is the
type that we've got from here already, which
we require here as a type for our arguments.
So, this is a float. And the same goes for
our y argument, which is also a float. So,
this should all be within the box. I just
wrote it above here. But it would be better
to actually draw the diagram again. I just
want to simplify it and put it here for this
video within the box by writing it by hand
here. And we do not require a return type
here. And this is important because we apply
scale to the Picture at hand and change the
Picture. We do not get a copy of any Picture
or an additional picture. We change the original
Picture. And that's the difference to the
function here. Our method changes the object
at hand. And we can continue defining the
methods here by looking at the functions that
we had in the vector graphics example that
was introduced. And "color" changes the
color of the Picture and therefore requires a
color. Let's call it C. And then we've got
rotate, which takes a picture and a float
as we rotate the Picture itself. This would
be just float for an angle. So, let's call
it angle. And you we require a float. Once
again, we do not require a return type of
type Picture because we change the Picture.
Having the return type Picture here would
be wrong because we changed the Picture at
hand. Then we've got the move operation. When
you look at the function of move, it looks
exactly like scale. So, we can also take the
same definition for our method. So, the type
is the same, and we can also keep the same
names for our parameters. Because in this
case, we have also got an x and
a y-direction for moving. Now extent is an
operation that is not found here within the
definition of vector graphics as a function.
This is because it was mentioned later. So,
it was mentioned within the object orientation
already, but there we have the example again.
And there is extent defined as returning a
float value for Picture. So, we could think
about this like, we've got a picture already,
and when we call extent on it, we just want
to return the float value. So, this is different
from the other functions and also the other
methods. In this case, we do not have an argument.
So, that's why we have an opening and closing
bracket simply. And then the return type is
really important. Because this is a float
in this case. And this was already mentioned
within the lecture. So, we could have just
copied it from here because here, the correct
type is already defined. Now there is just
an extension to the task missing. While we
could think about the ampersand operator,
which was defined within the introduction
to the vector graphics example. Here it is.
So, it combines two pictures and results in
a picture. If we want to realize this within
the domain of object orientation within this
class diagram, we could extend our Picture
here and realize this as well. When we think
about it, we can realize it by adding a picture
to another picture. So, this way, we could
combine or change one Picture by adding another
Picture to it. That is why we could define
it like this we have an ampersand function
that takes one argument, which is the other
Picture. So, let's call it p. And this of
type Picture. And it will change the Picture
at hand by calling this method. We have then
another Picture here. So, in this way, we
could combine Pictures. Maybe some of you
thought about why we have an aggregation here
between Path and Point because the Path consists
of multiple Points. Why is it not a composition?
This depends on how we want to see the Path.
Because if it's like this, that every Point
of the Path exists only for the Path, then
we could say it is a composition. But in this
case, it's not possible for multiple Paths
to share the same Point. So, you would require
another Point with the same x and y value
for another Path if we have a composition
here. So, if we have an aggregation here,
then multiple Paths can share the same Point.
So, when you're thinking about composition
and aggregation, you can also think about
what you want to have in your specific problem.
Both ways are possible for Path. When we have
the composition, Points cannot be shared.
And every Path is on just that single Point.
When we have aggregation, then Points may
be shared between different paths. That's
it for this task.